http://www.susqu.edu/about-su/policies#disclaimer

Thank You
Search:
Academics
(current)
Privacy Policy for Website Traffic
Scope Please read the following carefully to understand our practices regarding your personal information. This policy applies to your use of our website and how personal information you provide to us via our website is stored, transferred, and processed.
Information we may collect about you We may collect and process the following information: You may provide personal information by filling in forms on our website, or by corresponding with us (for example, via online forms or email). This information may include: - Contact information, such as including email and postal address, phone numbers, payment information - Records of any correspondence
How we use this information We use the information you provide to understand your needs and to improve the content and services we offer via our website, and to provide services which you request.
Disclosure of your information We may disclose the information which we collect or which you provide with Susquehanna University schools, departments, and offices and its contracted services, for the purpose of providing you service and/or for the academic and business purposes of Susquehanna University.
We will not sell, distribute, or lease your personal information to unaffiliated parties unless we have your permission, except where a duty to disclose or share your personal data is necessary to comply with legal or regulatory obligations or requests.
Storage of your personal data The information that we collect from you will be stored, transferred, and processed within the United States of America. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this storing, transferring, and/or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. In order to prevent unauthorized access, we have appropriate physical, technical, and administrative controls and procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.
Unfortunately, information transmitted via the Internet is inherently not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to us; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use appropriate security procedures to prevent unauthorized access, but this cannot be guaranteed.
Cookies We use cookies to identify which pages are being used on our website. This helps us analyze data about web page traffic and to improve our website. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes. You may choose to decline cookies for our website. However, this may prevent you from taking full advantage of our website.
Overall, cookies help us provide a better web experience by enabling us to monitor which pages are visited often and which are not useful. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the information you choose to share with us.
You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of our website.
Links to other websites Our website may contain links to other web sites not operated by Susquehanna University. Such sites are not governed by this policy. We are not responsible for the protection and privacy of any information you provide while visiting such websites.
Access to information Residents of the European Union (EU)/European Economic Area (EEA) have the right to access information stored about them. This right can be exercised in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) via the Data Protection Officer’s contact information below. There may be a fee for this access. Additional provisions related to information access will be handled by the Data Protection Officer.
Changes to privacy policy This policy may be reviewed and revised at any time.
Contact informationSusquehanna University 514 University Ave. Selinsgrove, PA 17870
Conditions of Use
The Office of Information Technology (IT) is responsible for the centrally managed information technology activities of Susquehanna University. It develops and provides services to benefit other segments of the University and to facilitate the success of decentralized information technology activities.
IT serves a large number and variety of users - faculty, staff, students, and outside clients. As members of the Susquehanna University community and in accordance with the overall policy in this area, all types of users have the responsibility to use IT's services in an effective, efficient, ethical, and legal manner.
Ethical and legal standards that apply to information technology resources derive directly from standards of common sense and common decency that apply to the use of any shared resource. IT depends first upon the spirit of mutual respect and cooperation that has been fostered at Susquehanna University to resolve differences and ameliorate problems that arise from time to time.
This statement on conditions of use is published in that spirit. The purpose of the statement is to promote the responsible, ethical, legal, and secure use of IT resources for the protection of all users.
Authorized Use
When you use ITs services, you agree to the following conditions:
To respect the privacy of other users; for example, you shall not intentionally seek information on, obtain copies of, or modify files, tapes, or passwords belonging to other users or the university, or represent others (i.e., log on as someone else), unless explicitly authorized to do so by those users.
To respect the legal protection provided by copyright and licensing of programs and data; for example, you shall not make copies of a licensed computer program to avoid paying additional license fees or to share with other users.
To respect the intended usage of accounts; for example, you shall use assigned accounts, transactions, data, and processes authorized by faculty, department heads, or project directors for the purposes specified, and shall not access or use other accounts, transactions, data, or processes unless explicitly authorized to do so by the authorizing personnel.
To respect the integrity of the system or network; for example, you shall not intentionally develop or use programs, transactions, data, or processes that harass other users or infiltrate the system or damage or alter the software or data components of a system. Alterations to any system or network software or data component shall be made only under specific instructions from authorized faculty, department heads, project directors, or management staff.
To respect the rights of other users; for example, you shall comply with all university policies regarding sexual, racial, and other forms of harassment, and you shall not divulge sensitive personal data concerning faculty, staff, or students to which you have access without explicit authorization to do so.
To adhere to all general university policies and procedures including, but not limited to, policies on proper use of information resources, information technology, and networks; acquisition, use, and disposal of university-owned computer equipment; use of telecommunications equipment; ethical and legal use of software; and ethical and legal use of administrative data.
The electronic mail system may not be used for the following:
Mass e-mail of any kind. A mass e-mail is defined as any e-mail or combination of e-mails sent to more that 50 recipients. The University Bulletin Board offers a web-based area for mass communication to the University community.
Chain letters.
Buying or selling items. The Electronic Newsletter and Bulletin Board offers a web-based area to post items for sale or items desired for purchase. Please note that no university resources may be used as part of a for-profit venture by any individual or group.
A request for or offer of a ride. The Electronic Newsletter and Bulletin Board offers a web-based area to request or offer rides.
Items lost or found. The Electronic Newsletter and Bulletin Board offers a web-based area to post items that have been lost or found.
These policies are established to assure access and ease of use for all in the University community. If a student fails to comply with these policies, his or her e-mail privileges will be revoked for two weeks. A second violation will result in revocation of e-mail privileges of two months, and a third violation will result in revocation of e-mail privileges for the remainder of the semester. A violation in the last week of the semester will result in the penalties being applied in the next semester. Any action that intentionally interferes with or harms the e-mail system will be dealt with as an attack on the University information technology system and receive much more stringent penalties.
In addition, other external networks to which Susquehanna University maintains connections (e.g., INTERNET) have established acceptable use standards. It is your responsibility to adhere to the standards of such networks. The University cannot and will not extend any protection to you should you violate the policies of an external network.
You should be aware that although IT provides and preserves security of files, account numbers, authorization codes, and passwords, security can be breached through actions or causes beyond the reasonable control of IT. You are urged, therefore, to safeguard your data, authorization codes, and passwords; to take full advantage of file security mechanisms built into the computing systems; to change your account password frequently; and to follow the security policies and procedures established to control access to and use of administrative data.
Violations of Conditions of Use
Violations of any of the above conditions are certainly unethical and may be violations of University policy or criminal offenses. You are expected to report to IT instances in which the above conditions have been or are being violated. When IT becomes aware of possible violations of these conditions, it will initiate an investigation. At the same time, in order to prevent further possible unauthorized activity, IT may suspend the authorization of computing services to the individual or account in question. In accordance with established University practices, policies and procedures, confirmation of unauthorized use of IT's resources may result in disciplinary review, expulsion from the University, termination of employment, legal action, or other disciplinary action.
Appropriate and Responsible Use
Computing resources shall be used in a manner consistent with the instruction, public service, research, and administrative objectives of the University, in general, and consistent with the specific objectives of the project or task for which such use was authorized, in particular. All uses inconsistent with these objectives, even if authorized, are considered to be inappropriate use and may jeopardize further authorization.
You are expected to use computing resources in a responsible and efficient manner. IT will provide guidance to help you use these resources efficiently and productively. If you use large amounts of computing and data processing resources, you are expected to refrain from engaging in deliberately wasteful practices - for example, printing large amounts of unnecessary listings, maintaining large numbers of unused files, or playing games for purely recreational purposes.
The pertinent consideration is the recognition that computing resources are finite. Therefore, you are expected to cooperate to the greatest extent possible in making these resources available to others.
IT's resources include systems for human interaction, such as messaging and conferencing. IT supports both freedom of expression in these media and the University's policies against racial, sexual, and other forms of harassment. Susquehanna University is committed to being a racially, ethnically, and religiously heterogeneous community.
Computer conferences in particular provide a vehicle through which the University's commitment can be realized, because they convene a very broad cross section of the community to discuss a wide range of issues, including those of bigotry, racism, and sexism. While using various media for electronic communication, you should be mindful of the impact of your contributions on the campus community. You should abide by the standards set for participant behavior in each conference you are in, as well as by standards of good citizenship and those described in University codes of conduct. Be mindful that you represent Susquehanna in outside conferences and that outside users will judge Susquehanna by your conduct.
Use of administrative data carries with it particular responsibilities for the security of data, userIDs, and passwords made available to access such data. As an administrative data user, you are responsible for properly safeguarding any administrative data which may be accessed by a terminal, personal computer, or any other distributed workstation. You should store data on storage media, such as floppy disks, in a secure environment consistent with the security classification of the data.
Your administrative userID defines the access authorization level appropriate for your job function, and you are considered responsible for all activity that occurs under your administrative userIDs and passwords. For this reason, you should not store userIDs and passwords in a microcomputer system, nor should you share your userIDs and passwords with others. You are also considered responsible for being aware of security policies and procedures relating to access and use of administrative data.
IT Responsibilities
IT has a responsibility to provide service in the most efficient manner while considering the needs of the total user community. At certain times, the process of carrying out these responsibilities may require special actions or intervention by the staff. At all other times, IT staff have no special rights above and beyond those of other users. IT shall make every effort to ensure that persons in positions of trust do not misuse computing resources or data or take advantage of their positions to access information not required in the performance of their duties.
IT prefers not to act as a disciplinary agency or to police activities. However, in cases of unauthorized, inappropriate, or irresponsible behavior, IT does reserve the right to take remedial action, commencing with an investigation of the possible abuse. In this connection, IT, with all due regard for the rights of privacy, shall have the authority to examine files, passwords, accounting information, printouts, tapes, or other material that may aid the investigation. Examination of your files must be authorized by the appropriate IT Senior Manager or designee. You, when requested, are expected to cooperate in such investigations. Failure to do so may be grounds for cancellation of access privileges.
You can direct questions about this conditions of use statement and reports of possible violations of the conditions of use to the IT Reception Desk (372-4252).
Privacy Statement
Susquehanna University respects your privacy and will protect the information you share with the university through any means of communication. This statement explains how Susquehanna University collects, safeguards and may use the information you entrust to the university via the Susquehanna University World Wide Web site, comprising but not limited to the hosts www.susqu.edu, search.susqu.edu, webmail.susqu.edu, blackboard.susqu.edu, and websu.susqu.edu.
Server logs
Susquehanna's Web hosts collect and store information sent by your Web browser. This information includes:
The Internet Protocol (IP) address associated with the device in use, such as a personal computer, hand-held device or the firewall or proxy server of the user's network The date and time the Web browser made the request
The address (URL) of the page or file requested
The address (URL) of the "referring page," the page the browser loaded immediately before the request
"User agent" information, which usually includes information about the browser software and operating system the computer or device is currently running
General technical data about Susquehanna's server health and activity at the time of the request
This information does not reveal personally identifiable information but allows Susquehanna to analyze trends in how university systems are being used. This information, including reports generated from the information, is stored indefinitely by the university. Reports may occasionally be shared with third party vendors for further analysis. By having this information available, Susquehanna is able to improve the performance and user experience of the Susquehanna Web site.
Cookies
Susquehanna may use "cookies," small text files placed on your computer's own hard disk drive by university systems, which make it possible for those systems to determine if a specific computer has made previous requests. They do not collect or store any personally identifiable information, and Susquehanna does not combine information collected through cookies with other personal information to determine who you are. The use of cookies allows Susquehanna to enhance the user experience of the Susquehanna web site. Cookies are not required to browse the Susquehanna web site, except when using secure web services.
Secure Web services
When using web services provided by Susquehanna, you may be asked to authenticate or log on, using a user name and password. Susquehanna provides user names and initial passwords to campus community members. Susquehanna provides user names and initial passwords to friends of the university for certain services upon completion of a registration process. Users will be required to change their initial password and may also be required to change it periodically thereafter. Passwords are stored in an encrypted or scrambled format while residing on university systems.
Information transferred between your web browser and university systems during the use of web services is encrypted. To provide this capability, Susquehanna uses a network protocol known as Secure Socket Layer (SSL), a certificate-based 128-bit encryption protocol that establishes a secure Internet session and ensures that the information you submit is accessible only to you and university systems. You can determine whether or not web pages are secure by looking at the address (URL) of the web page being viewed.
An "s" at the end of "http" (https:) indicates that you are attached to a secure server with SSL technology. This prevents unauthorized individuals from eavesdropping on your private information while you communicate with Susquehanna.
Susquehanna web services require the use of a "session cookie" to facilitate the establishment of a session. A session cookie stores unique identification data that allow Susquehanna to confirm that you are the only person university systems are communicating with during this session. This cookie only exists for as long as you are logged on to the session. Without the session cookie, you will not be able to use the web services provided by Susquehanna. If you prefer to not accept cookies in general, you can specify an exception in your web browser settings for the domain "susqu.edu". A "log off" button is provided to terminate your session and further protect your private information.
Information collection
Susquehanna may collect information from a user, with the user's permission, for the purpose of providing various services or improving the overall content and user experience of the web site. This information may be shared with other persons or departments within the university to provide a requested service but will not be shared with any third party without your express consent. The only exceptions would be in order to conduct normal university business (for example: providing credit card information to a payment processor to complete a payment transaction) or when Susquehanna is legally required to disclose information in response to a court issued subpoena or legally permissible inquiry by a governmental agency or regulator. Susquehanna does not distribute or sell lists of e-mail addresses for commercial purposes but may occasionally provide lists to third party affiliates who are rendering services on behalf of the university.
Outside links
Susquehanna's web content may link to content located on Internet servers not owned or affiliated with Susquehanna. These third party web sites are neither monitored nor controlled by Susquehanna. As a result, this policy does not extend to those sites.
Circumstances beyond the university's control
While Susquehanna strives to protect its users' personal information and privacy, it cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose online, and you do so at your own risk. Susquehanna's policy does not extend to anything that is inherent in the operation of the Internet and therefore beyond the university's control and is not to be applied in any manner contrary to applicable law or governmental regulation.
Right to change policy
Susquehanna reserves the right at its discretion to make changes to this policy at any time. Changes will be posted to the Susquehanna Web site prior to becoming effective. Approved December 2005, Web Steering Committee.
Web Disclaimer
Susquehanna University provides facilities for students, faculty and staff to create personal web pages. Some personal pages contain information about university instructional, research, administrative or public service programs. Other pages include personal interests, avocations, artistic expressions and links to Internet resources.
Susquehanna University does not preview, censor, nor control the content of these pages in any way as a matter of course. Authors of these pages are responsible for obeying all relevant laws and University Policies. Views expressed in personal pages are strictly those of the page authors, to whom any comments on their contents should be directed.
